<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zshzero</title>
    <link>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on zshzero</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:00:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zshzero.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 1</title>
      <link>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/gsoc/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:00:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/gsoc/week1/</guid>
      <description>This week, I built toolchain for crOS (will be referring to ChromiumOS this entire series)
My first attempt was to create binary package for toolchain packages using crossdev
 Create an overlay specifically for crossdev&amp;rsquo;s use  mkdir -p /var/db/repos/crossdev mkdir -p /var/db/repos/crossdev/{profiles,metadata} echo &amp;#39;crossdev&amp;#39; &amp;gt; /var/db/repos/crossdev/profiles/repo_name echo &amp;#39;masters = gentoo&amp;#39; &amp;gt; /var/db/repos/crossdev/metadata/layout.conf chown -R portage:portage /var/db/repos/crossdev  Then instruct portage and crossdev to use this overlay:  #FILE /etc/portage/repos.conf/crossdev.conf [crossdev] location = /var/db/repos/crossdev priority = 10 masters = gentoo auto-sync = no  Install crossdev and build toolchain for crOS:  emerge --ask crossdev crossdev --stable -t x86_64-cros-linux-gnu  After building toolchain, use quickpkg to create binary packages of them:  quickpkg cross-x86-cros-linux-gnu/binutils quickpkg cross-x86-cros-linux-gnu/gcc quickpkg cross-x86-cros-linux-gnu/gdb quickpkg cross-x86-cros-linux-gnu/glibc quickpkg cross-x86-cros-linux-gnu/linux-headers   Created binary packages are pointed to by the PKGDIR variable which defaults to /var/cache/binpkgs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Install Chromium OS dev</title>
      <link>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/gsoc/build-and-install-chromium-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 06:47:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/gsoc/build-and-install-chromium-os/</guid>
      <description>This post is a quick start guide to get the Chromium OS source and build it.
The official guide is at: Developer Guide
These are the steps and commands I used while following the official guide:
Prerequisite: You must have any up-to-date Linux distribution on a x86_64 64-bit system with sudo access to develop Chromium OS (They recommend and offer support to Ubuntu 16.04 - Xenial)  Install git revision control system, the curl download helper, and lvm tools  sudo apt-get install git-core gitk git-gui curl lvm2 \  thin-provisioning-tools python-pkg-resources python-virtualenv \  python-oauth2client xz-utils python3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>I am an active member of the Open Source Community called OSL which works for the cause of promoting and contributing to Free and Open Source Software.
Having used GNU/Linux for quite some time now and recently I moved to Gentoo. Since then I have been closely following the Gentoo project and participating actively. Also, I have a few contributions to the community.
As a hobby project, I have been working on FridayOS which was done referring to intermezzOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is my Project all about?</title>
      <link>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zshzero.github.io/blog/project/</guid>
      <description>Chromium OS, an open-source project that aims to provide a fast, simple, and more secure computing experience for people who spend most of their time on the web and Chromebook is a special-purpose device for a group of users who only care about the web.
But Portage, the package manager which was originally developed for Gentoo Linux and other tools are used only for cross-compiling and building the filesystem image which makes it a feature-limited OS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>